Rikesh Shrestha

Kathmandu, Nepal | +977-9861752607 | sr1k3sh@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

Enthusiastic Frontend Developer eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Clear understanding of frontend technologies. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in Web Development.

Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 4+ years, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

EDUCATION

Msc IT., Applied science | running | ISLINGTON COLLEGE

B.E., Computer science and engineering | Graduation date: June 2016 | VTU (Bangalore,IN)

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER | NORTH AMERICAN WEB | KATHMANDU, AUG 2016 - FEB 2017

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Collaborated with the marketing department to determine organizational needs and design pages to meet goals.
- Drafted customized layout and wireframes based on predetermined parameters and expectations.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | ARRTSM GMBH KAHTMANDU, DECEMBER 2016 - FEBRUARY 2018

- Developed Augmented Reality App in Android platform using java/xml
- Web development (wordpress)

Web Developer | Gsignal X Pvt Ltd | Kathmandu, February 2018 - December 2019

- Developed Design system on React
- Lead team on the project

Frontend Developer | Itonics Nepal | Kathmandu, January 2020 - October 2021

- Design/developed features request from Project manager within the deadline
- Debug bugs on daily basis using debugging tool on chrome/firefox/ie11
- Wrote ie11 compatible code at the beginning
- ES6 code on webpack for specific feature on isolated repo for future use
- Wrote isolated features i.e toast/nodegraph/filters/mention

- Played keyrole on challenges/problem that came from client and fixed within time with positive feedback from client
- Self learned angular framework to enhance my skill by making a weather app

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | FREELANCER | KATHMANDU, OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Design system on fractal
- Semantic HTML ui with accessibility tested
- Schema test
- Mobile first approach on design system

CORE SKILLS

SOFTWARE

- VScode
- Android studio

PROGRAMMING

- Javascript
- Jquery
- java

PREPROCESSORS

SASS/SCSS

FRAMEWORKS

- Basic understanding Angular
- Intermediate on React
- Basic on webpack/gulp

LANGUAGES

- English
- Nepali

INTERESTS

- Video games: Basically anything
- Sports: Mountain Biking, swimming
- Instruments: guitar

LINKS

• https://app.netlify.com/teams/sr1k3sh/sites

• https://www.linkedin.com/in/rikesh-shrestha-62539b111/